Curriculum vitae

Avinita Kumari

D.O.B. Apr 07, 1990 Language: English, Hindi

E mail: avinita90@gmail.com

Contact: +91-9969537994, +91-8850526572

Address: A-402, Palam Apartments, Sector 5, Dwarka, New Delhi-110075

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Enthusiastic Physics teacher with **5+ years** of experience, helping students appreciate Science through **observation**, **experimentation** and **reasoning**. Developing critical thinking skills, problem solving and curiosity in high school students. I have a demonstrated history of teaching in Physics for both PGT and TGT standards. Skilled in **Team building & leadership**, **Student advocacy**, **Conflict resolution etc.** Strong Teaching professional with a **Master of Science and B.Ed** focused in **Physics**.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

- OPG World School, Dwarka, Delhi
- ➤ PGT Physics & Science coordinator [June 2017- November 2019]
- Teaching Physics to grade 11 and 12 and Science to grade 10 and grade 6.
- ➤ Maintaining uniformity in lesson transaction from grade 6 to grade 12.
- Designing and Conducting science competitions and workshops for students.
- > Organizing science week.
- Attended capacity building workshop conducted by CBSE and various workshops by IAPT (Indian Association of Physics Teachers).
- ➤ Volunteered and organized a summer trip to the east coast of the USA (NASA) for students from grade 6 to 12 students.
- Vidyagyan Leadership Academy (Shiv Nadar Foundation)
- > TGT Physics [April 2016- January 2017]
- ➤ Designed lesson plans and taught Physics to grade 10th, 11th and Science to grade 7th and 9th.
- ➤ Conducted Science hobby classes for students after school hours.
- Attended workshops on "Learning science through experimentation".
- Mentored and provided coaching to students for NTSE (National Talent Search Examination).
- Army Public School, Mumbai
 - **PGT Physics** (June 2015- March 2016)
- ➤ Designed lesson plans and taught grade 10th, 11th and 12th.
- Diamond Jubilee High School (Aga Khan Educational Trust), Mumbai (ICSE)

Assistant Teacher (June 2012- March 2013)

- ➤ Designed lesson plans and taught grade 5th, 7th and 8th.
- Zilla Parishad High School, Madanapalli (Andhra Pradesh)

Internship (2 months)

- ➤ Designed lesson plans and taught grade 8th and 9th.
- **Tutoring** (2012- 2015)
- Tutored students of IB and IGCSE A level Physics and Science for grade 6th to 8th, CBSE grade 10th, 11th and 12th physics and ICSE board grade 10 physics.

EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

Qualification	Institution	University/Board	Year of passing	Percentage
MSc Physics (Microprocessor and Microcontrollers)	D.G Ruparel College	Mumbai University	April 2015	55
BSc.Ed(PCM)	Regional institute of Education (NCERT)	Mysore University	2012	73
XII	Kendriya Vidayalaya Visakhapatnam	CBSE	2008	72
X	Kendriya Vidayalaya Visakhapatnam	CBSE	2006	84

ACHIEVEMENTS

- ➤ Qualified CTET (Central Teachers Eligibility Test)
- Qualified CSB (Combined selection board)
- Qualified CDS(Combined Defence Services)
- Selected for 'Teach for India' fellowship for the year 2013-2015
- ➤ Recipient of NCERT meritorious scholarship
- > Recipient of INBA (Indian Navy Benevolent Association) scholarship
- ➤ Won 2nd prize in intercollegiate quiz competition on NCERT golden jubilee
- ➤ Won 1st prize in Table Tennis at college level
- Awarded 0.1 certificate in 10th grade for securing 97 marks in Hindi.

DECLARATION

I hereby state that all the above furnished information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: New Delhi yours truly, Avinita Kumari